hibike.com 2018-12-10

# help-info-hibike-s-privacy-policy

_The following translation is for your information only. In the event of a conflict or contradiction between this translated version and the German version (including as a result of translation delays), the German version shall prevail._

### Data protection declaration

Thank you for your interest in our online shop. The protection of your privacy is very important to us. Below we inform you in detail about the handling of your data. 

#### 1\. Access data and hosting

You can visit our website without providing any personal information. Each time a website is called up, the web server automatically saves a so-called server log file which, for example, contains the name of the requested file, your IP address, date and time of the call, the amount of data transmitted and the requesting provider (access data) and documents the call. These access data are evaluated exclusively for the purpose of ensuring trouble-free operation of the site and improving our offer. Pursuant to Article 6, paragraph 1, sentence 1, letter f GDPR, this serves to safeguard our legitimate interests in a correct presentation of our offer, which predominate within the scope of a balancing of interests. All access data will be deleted no later than seven days after the end of your visit to the site. 

#### Third-party hosting services

As part of processing on our behalf, a third party provider provides us with hosting and website presentation services. This serves to protect our legitimate interests in a correct presentation of our offer, which predominate within the scope of a balancing of interests. All data collected in the context of the use of this website or in the forms provided for this purpose in the online shop as described below are processed on its servers. Processing on other servers only takes place in the framework described here. 

This service provider is located within a country of the European Union or the European Economic Area. 

#### 2\. Data collection and use for contract processing and when opening a customer account

We collect personal data when you voluntarily provide it to us in connection with your order, when contacting us (e.g. via contact form or e-mail) or when opening a customer account. Mandatory fields are marked as such, since in these cases we require the data for contract processing, or for processing your contact or opening of the customer account, and you cannot complete the order and/or the account opening or can not send the contact without their information. Which data is collected can be seen from the respective input forms. We use the data provided by you in accordance with Article 6, paragraph 1, sentence 1, letter b GDPR for contract processing and processing your enquiries. After complete processing of the contract or deletion of your customer account, your data will be restricted for further processing and deleted after expiry of the storage periods under tax and commercial law, unless you have expressly consented to further use of your data or we reserve the right to use data beyond this, which is permitted by law and about which we inform you in this declaration. The deletion of your customer account is possible at any time and can take place either via a message to the contact possibility described below or via a function intended for it in the customer account. 

#### 3\. Data transfer

In order to fulfil the contract in accordance with Article 6, paragraph 1, sentence 1, letter b GDPR, we pass on your data to the shipping company commissioned with the delivery, insofar as this is necessary for the delivery of ordered goods. Depending on which payment service provider you select in the order process, we pass on the payment data collected for the processing of payments to the credit institution commissioned with the payment and, if applicable, to payment service providers commissioned by us or to the selected payment service. In some cases, the selected payment service providers also collect this data themselves if you create an account there. In this case, you must log in to the payment service provider with your access data during the ordering process. The data protection declaration of the respective payment service provider applies in this respect. 

We use payment service providers based in a country outside the European Union. The transmission of personal data to this company only takes place within the scope of the necessity to fulfil the contract. 

#### 4\. E-mail newsletter and postal advertising

**E-mail advertising with registration for the newsletter**  
If you register for our newsletter, we use the data required for this or separately communicated by you in order to regularly send you our e-mail newsletter on the basis of your consent in accordance with Article 6, paragraph 1, sentence 1, letter a GDPR. 

You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time and either by sending a message to the contact option described below or via a link provided for this purpose in the newsletter. After deregistration, we delete your e-mail address unless you have expressly consented to further use of your data or we reserve the right to use data beyond this, which is permitted by law and about which we inform you in this declaration. 

**E-mail advertising without registration for the newsletter and your right of objection**  
If we receive your e-mail address in connection with the sale of a product or service and you have not objected to this, we reserve the right to regularly send you offers for similar products, such as those already purchased, from our range by e-mail on the basis of Section 7 (3) UWG. This serves to protect our legitimate interests in an advertising approach to our customers, which outweigh our interests. 

You can object to this use of your e-mail address at any time by sending a message to the contact option described below or via a link provided for this purpose in the advertising mail, without incurring any costs other than the transmission costs according to the basic rates. 

**Postal advertising and your right of objection**  
Furthermore, we reserve the right to use your first and last name as well as your postal address for our own advertising purposes, e.g. to send interesting offers and information about our products by post. This serves to safeguard our legitimate interests in an advertising approach to our customers in accordance with Article 6, paragraph 1, sentence 1, letter f GDPR, which predominate in the context of a weighing of interests. 

#### 5\. Use of data for payment processing

**Hire purchase**

When selecting the payment method "hire purchase" and granting the data protection consent required for this in accordance with Article 6, paragraph 1, sentence 1, letter a GDPR, personal data (first name, surname, address, e-mail, telephone number, date of birth, IP address, gender) together with data required for transaction processing (article, invoice amount, due dates, total amount, invoice number, taxes, currency, order date and order time) will be transmitted to our partner Santander Consumer Bank AG, Santander-Platz 1, 41061 Mönchengladbach for purposes of processing this payment method. 

To verify the identity or creditworthiness of the customer, our partner carries out inquiries and information with publicly accessible databases and credit bureaus. The providers from whom information and, if applicable, creditworthiness information is obtained on the basis of mathematical-statistical procedures, as well as further details on the processing of your data after transmission to our partner Santander Consumer Bank AG, please refer to its data protection declaration, which you can find here: https://www.santander.de/privatkunden/service-kontakt/datenschutz/ 

Our partner Santander Consumer Bank AG uses the information received on the statistical probability of non-payment for a balanced decision on the establishment, implementation or termination of the contractual relationship. You have the opportunity to express your views by contacting our partner Santander Consumer Bank AG and to challenge the decision. 

The consent to the transfer of data given in the order process can be revoked at any time, even without giving reasons, with effect for the future. 

**Credit card purchase**

When selecting the payment method "credit card" and granting the necessary data protection consent required for this in accordance with Article 6, paragraph 1, sentence 1, letter a GDPR, personal data (e-mail address, country of delivery of the order) together with data required for transaction processing (total amount, invoice number, taxes, currency, order date and order time) will be transmitted to our partner SIX Payment Services (Europe) S.A. (10, Rue Gabriel Lippmann, L-5365 Munsbach, Luxembourg) for the purpose of processing this type of payment. 

For statistical risk assessment purposes, our partner sends the e-mail address and the country of delivery to Fraugster Ltd. (Engeldamm 64b, 10179 Berlin, Germany). On the basis of the results of the risk assessment, SIX Payment Services decides whether the customer must undergo the 3D Secure procedure, which may achieve a reversal of liability of the credit card payment in order to relieve us of the risk of non-payment. This risk assessment has no effect on the availability of the payment method "credit card", it only serves to make the payment process easier for the customer. 

#### 6\. Integration of the Trusted Shops Trustbadge

The Trusted Shops Trustbadge is included on this website to display our Trusted Shops seal of approval and the collected evaluations as well as to offer Trusted Shops products to buyers after an order. 

This serves to safeguard our legitimate interests in an optimal marketing of our offer in accordance with Article 6, paragraph 1, sentence 1, letter f GDPR, which predominate in the context of a balancing of interests. The Trustbadge and the services advertised with it are an offer of Trusted Shops GmbH, Subbelrather Str. 15C, 50823 Cologne. 

When calling the trust badge, the web server automatically saves a so-called server log file, which contains e.g. your IP address, date and time of the call, transferred data volume and the requesting provider (access data) and documents the call. This access data is not evaluated and is automatically overwritten at the latest seven days after the end of your page visit. 

Further personal data will only be transferred to Trusted Shops if you have consented to this, decide to use Trusted Shops products after completing an order or have already registered for use. In this case the contractual agreement between you and Trusted Shops applies. 

#### 7\. Cookies and web analysis

To make visiting our website attractive and to enable the use of certain functions, to display suitable products or for market research purposes, we use so-called cookies on various pages. This serves to safeguard our legitimate interests in an optimised presentation of our offer in accordance with Article 6, paragraph 1, sentence 1, letter f GDPR, which predominate in the context of a balancing of interests. 

Cookies are small text files that are automatically stored on your internet device. Some of the cookies we use are deleted after the end of the browser session, i.e. after closing your browser (so-called session cookies). Other cookies remain on your terminal and enable us to recognize your browser on your next visit (persistent cookies). You can see the duration of storage in the overview in the cookie settings of your web browser. 

You can set your browser in such a way that you are informed about the setting of cookies and decide individually about their acceptance or exclude the acceptance of cookies for certain cases or generally. Each browser differs in the way it manages the cookie settings. This is described in the help menu of each browser, which explains how you can change your cookie settings. You can find these for each browser under the following links: 

  * Internet Explorer™: http://windows.microsoft.com/de-DE/windows-vista/Block-or-allow-cookies
  * Safari™: https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_DE
  * Chrome™: http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&hlrm=en&answer=95647
  * Opera™: http://help.opera.com/Windows/10.20/de/cookies.html
  * Firefox™: https://support.mozilla.org/de/kb/cookies-erlauben-und-ablehnen

If cookies are not accepted, the functionality of our website may be restricted. 

#### Use of Google (Universal) Analytics for web analysis

For website analysis, this website uses Google (Universal) Analytics, a web analysis service of Google LLC (www.google.de). This serves to safeguard our legitimate interests in an optimised presentation of our offer in accordance with Article 6, paragraph 1, sentence 1, letter f GDPR, which predominate in the context of a balancing of interests. 

Google (Universal) Analytics uses methods that enable an analysis of your use of the website, such as cookies. The automatically collected information about your use of this website is usually transferred to a Google server in the USA and stored there. By activating IP anonymisation on this website, the IP address is reduced prior to transmission within the Member States of the European Union or in other states party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. The anonymous IP address transmitted by your browser within the framework of Google Analytics is not merged with other Google data. After the end of the use of Google Analytics by us the data collected in this context will be deleted. 

Google LLC is headquartered in the USA and is certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield. A current certificate can be viewed [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). 

As a result of this agreement between the US and the European Commission, the latter has established an adequate level of data protection for companies certified under the Privacy Shield.You can prevent Google from collecting the data generated by the cookie and relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) and from processing this data by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available under the following link: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en 

As an alternative to the browser plug-in, you can click this link to prevent future collection by Google Analytics on this website. An opt-out cookie is stored on your internet device. If you delete your cookies, you must click the link again. 

#### 8\. Voucher offers of Sovendus GmbH

In order to select a currently interesting voucher offer for you, we will transmit your pseudonymised hash value of your e-mail address and your IP-address in encrypted form to Sovendus GmbH, Moltkestrasse 11, D-76133 Karlsruhe (Sovendus) (Article 6, paragraph 1, letter f GDPR). The pseudonymised hash value of your e-mail address is used to consider a possibly existing objection to receive offers from Sovendus (Article 21, paragraph 3 and Article 6, paragraph 1, letter c GDPR). 

The IP-address will be exclusively used for data security purposes and as a rule the same will be anonymised after seven days (Article 6, paragraph 1, letter f DSGVO). Furthermore, we will transmit order number, order value with currency, session ID, coupon code, and time stamp in pseudonymised form to Sovendus for billing purposes (Article 6, paragraph 1, letter f DSGVO). 

If you are interested in a voucher offer of Sovendus, while there is no objection existing to receive such offers, and if you click on the voucher banner, we will transmit your form of address, your name and your e-mail address in encrypted form to Sovendus to prepare a voucher (Article 6, paragraph 1, letters b,f GDPR). 

You will find further information about the processing of your data by Sovendus in their Online Data Protection Notice at <http://www.sovendus.co.uk/privacy_policy>

#### 9\. Contact possibilities and your rights

As a person concerned, you have the following rights: 

  * pursuant to article 15 GDPR the right to request information about your personal data processed by us to the extent described therein;
  * pursuant to article 16 GDPR the right to demand immediately the correction of incorrect or complete personal data stored by us;
  * pursuant to article 17 GDPR the right to request the deletion of your personal data stored with us, unless further processing is required 
    * to exercise the right to freedom of expression and information; 
    * to fulfil a legal obligation; 
    * for reasons of public interest or 
    * to assert, exercise or defend legal claims 
  * pursuant to article 18 GDPR the right to request the restriction of the processing of your personal data if 
    * you dispute the accuracy of the data; 
    * the processing is unlawful, but you refuse to delete it; 
    * we no longer need the data, but you need it to assert, exercise or defend legal claims or 
    * you have filed an objection to the processing pursuant to article 21 GDPR 
  * pursuant to article 20 GDPR the right to receive your personal data that you have provided to us in a structured, current and machine-readable format or to request its transfer to another person responsible; 
  * pursuant to article 77 GDPR the right to complain to a supervisory authority. As a rule, you can contact the supervisory authority at your usual place of residence or workplace or at our company headquarters. 

If you have any questions regarding the collection, processing or use of your personal data, information, correction, blocking or deletion of data or revocation of consent given or objection to a specific use of data, please contact us directly via the contact data in our imprint. 

#### Right of objection

Insofar as we process personal data as described above in order to protect our legitimate interests, which predominate within the scope of a balance of interests, you can object to this processing with effect for the future. If the data is processed for direct marketing purposes, you can exercise this right at any time as described above. If the processing takes place for other purposes, you are only entitled to a right of objection if there are reasons arising from your particular situation. 

After exercising your right of objection, we will not process your personal data further for these purposes, unless we can prove compelling grounds for processing that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms or if the processing serves to assert, exercise or defend legal claims. 

This does not apply if processing is for direct marketing purposes. Then we will not process your personal data for this purpose. 

Last update: 28 November 2018
